<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NewMR on William Poynter</title>
    <link>https://www.williampoynter.co.uk/tags/newmr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NewMR on William Poynter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.williampoynter.co.uk/tags/newmr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why should I use international standards?</title>
      <link>https://www.williampoynter.co.uk/publications/internationalstandards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.williampoynter.co.uk/publications/internationalstandards/</guid>
      <description>Space is big. Really big. You just won’t believe how vastly, hugely, mind-bogglingly big it is. – Douglas Adams
 And now data is big too. Lots of you will have heard, or read, that in the past two years we have created more data than all previous years combined. And there appears to be no indication or reason to think that this rate of growth is going to slow down anytime soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open data, what does it mean and why do we need it?</title>
      <link>https://www.williampoynter.co.uk/publications/opendata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.williampoynter.co.uk/publications/opendata/</guid>
      <description>What is open data? I prefer to refer to opening up data, an action, rather than open data, a noun. This is because open data suggests an absolute state, while openness is relative to the environment and user. I.e. data is not either open or not, it exists along a spectrum depending who you are, what you would like to do with the data and where we are in the timeline of the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big data, what is it and will it be here to stay?</title>
      <link>https://www.williampoynter.co.uk/publications/bigdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.williampoynter.co.uk/publications/bigdata/</guid>
      <description>Although the term “big data” has been in use since the 1990s, it has gained popularity massively over the last 5 years.
Technological terms come in and out of fashion all of the time, e.g. we still have websites, but we do not call them the ‘World Wide Web’ anymore. We also see terminology evolve over time, e.g. ‘social network’ has been replaced by ‘social media’.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
